JEFFREY KAM

hykam@uwaterloo.ca \leq UWaterloo ID: 20716434

INTERESTS

I am interested in graph theory and graph algorithms research, with a particular interest in structural graph theory, graph drawing, and graph colouring. In addition, I am also keen on quantum computing and hope to learn more through courses like quantum information processing and algebraic graph theory in the future.

EDUCATION

University of Waterloo

Sep 2017 - Present

Currently in term 4A

- · Candidate for B.Math. in Combinatorics & Optimizations and Computer Science
- · Minor in Pure Mathematics

Relevant Courses

Taken already / Expected before Summer 2021.

- \cdot Graph-theoretic Algorithms CS762
- · Algorithms for Graph Minors CO749
- · Algebraic Graph Theory CO444 (expected)
- · Integer Programming CO452 (expected)
- · Introduction to Graph Theory CO342
- · Network Flow Theory CO351
- · Algorithms CS341
- · Statistical and Computational Foundations of Machine Learning CS485
- · Groups and Rings PMATH347
- · Algebraic Number Theory PMATH441
- · Complex Analysis PMATH352 (expected)
- · Formal Languages CS462 (expected)

Relevant Projects

· Bounded Queue-number in Planar Graphs (CS762) -

Explore a recent proof by Dujmović et al for a 20-year old conjectjure on whether the queue-number of planar graph is bounded.

· Tangles in Graph Minor X (CO749) -

Explore a new notion of connectivity in graph that arises in the Graph Minor project by Robertson and Seymour.

PUBLICATION

· UBCIS: Ultimate Benchmark for Container Image Scanning,

with Shay Berkovich and Glenn Wurster

Published in 13th USENIX Workshop on Cyber Security Experimentation and Test (CSET 20). https://www.usenix.org/conference/cset20/presentation/berkovich

· bioSyntax: Syntax Highlighting For Computational Biology,

with A. Babaian, et al.

Published in BMC Bioinformatics 19, 303 (2018).

https://doi.org/10.1186/s12859-018-2315-y

RESEARCH EXPERIENCE

University of Waterloo - Symbolic Computation Group

Undergraduate Research Assistant

May 2020 - Sep 2020 Waterloo, Canada

- · Experiment with J-ideal and Smith Normal Form using SAGE.
- · Understand relationships between matrix normal forms and ideals.

BlackBerry - Security Research Group

Security Research Intern

January 2020 - April 2020

Waterloo, Canada

- · Researched and designed a universal benchmark to quantitatively measure the effectiveness and accuracy of container image scanners
- · Analyzed techniques of image inspection and vulnerability scanning through open source technologies
- · Designed a universal import framework for Anchore Engine to extend our scanning capabilities
- · Researched on utilizing machine learning for fuzzing algorithmic complexity vulnerabilities (ACV)
- · Presented to the security research group on current developments of machine-learning-based fuzzing and fuzzing techniques for ACVs, along with potential problems, experiments, and optimizations.

WORK EXPERIENCE

GTS

Sep 2020 - Present

Software Engineering Intern

New York, US

· Working on performant C++ and Python code for the core trading engine

Zenefits

May 2019 - Aug 2019

Software Engineering Intern

Vancouver, Canada

- · Developed new permission services in Django with extensive unit tests to guard against unauthorized edits of review data
- · Designed a sequeitial document update service using a distributed messsage queue system Celery

Horizn

May 2018 - Aug 2018

Web Developer Intern

Toronto, Canada

- · Built Laravel components for internal app and wrote Python scripts to transfer clients' data in AWS
- · Wrote automation scripts to scrape data from files and database and compile them into json files

AWARDS

- · First place in HackSeq 2017 bioinformatics competition in UBC
- · Honourable mention in Canadian Computing Competition Hong Kong 2017
- · University of Waterloo President's Scholarship

SKILLS

Programming

Python, C++, SAGE, Scheme

Tools

Git, C++ tools (i.e. GCC, GDB, Valgrind), Docker, Linux, Jupyter